<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Longwen's Blog - Python</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/python.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2017-01-16T23:36:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Setting up python for macOS</title><link href="/setting-up-python-for-macos.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-01-16T23:36:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-01-16T23:36:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Longwen Ou</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-01-16:/setting-up-python-for-macos.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An introduction to my python setup&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://atom.io/"&gt;Atom&lt;/a&gt; is a cross-platform text editor developed by &lt;a href="https://github.com/"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. It is highly comtomizable with support for plug-ins. In this post we'll talk about setting up Atom for Python, Latex and web development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Atom settings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My atom settings looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/atom_theme.jpg' width=70%/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href="https://atom.io/themes/atom-material-ui"&gt;atom-material-ui&lt;/a&gt; UI theme and the corresponding syntax theme &lt;a href="https://atom.io/themes/atom-material-syntax"&gt;atom-material-syntax&lt;/a&gt;. I also installed &lt;a href="https://atom.io/packages/file-icons"&gt;file-icons&lt;/a&gt; to assign beautiful file extension icons and colors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Set up Atom for Python Programming&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a number of packages for python programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;autocomplete-python: provides autocompletion for Python packages, variables, methods, and functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;linter: a base linter provider. It provides a top-level API to other packages to visualize errors and other kind-of messages, easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;linter-flake8: a flake8 provider for linter. It requires installation of flake8 python package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;linter-pep8: provides an interface to pep8. It requires installation of pep8 python package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;python-tools: provides handy tools for developing Python code. It bring feature such as Goto Definition, Select String Contents, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you'are ready to have some fun developing Python code with atom. Congrats :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is a popular programming language. Python comes with macOS. However, it is not recommended
to use the system python for development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installing python on macOS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two ways of installing python on macOS. The first way is to install python from source.  &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="atom"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="macOS"></category></entry></feed>